Matthew Solc - Resume

720-251-6538

132 Marginal Way Apt 232C South Portland, ME

matthewsolc66@gmail.com

| GitHub |

My name is Matthew Solc. I am a graduate of Skyline High School in Longmont. I was in the STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math) Academy. The summer of Freshman year I completed my ACMT (Apple Certified Mac Technician) Certification and Sophomore summer I re-certified with ACMT and ACiT (Apple Certified iOS Technician). Skyline did not offer many automotive classes, so all my experience is self taught.

I am interested in working in Computer Science and Software Development. I have learned several programming languages, including Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, and C++. I have learned the Linux Command Line and am very comfortable using it. I have set up my own systems using Arch Linux and Gentoo.

I am also interested in working in the automotive world. I have become very self reliant when it comes to cars. My first car, a 2007 Saab 93, fell victim to a strong rainstorm and suffered engine flooding. I was able to fix it after clearing out the intake, cylinders and exhaust. I also installed a new starter which in a Saab, is no small feat. I came across a second car, a 2005 Acura TL, which I have been putting work into non stop. Cold air intake, new alternator, new brake rotors, calipers, and pads. I also have done CV axles and radiators, intake manifolds and valve covers. I am very hands on with my vehicles and am never going to stop learning new things.

Past Employment

Innovation Center - StVrain Valley School District - August 2015 - May 2018

TechTeam

Hardware and software support for Apple products and devices

Co-Teaching Tech2 Class

Summer 2016 - I co-taught the Tech 2 class at the summer STEM institute.

Website Design

Fall 2016, myself and 2 others designed a website for a coach hoping to create a blog about health and exercise routines. CoachCloie

District Technology Services - StVrain Valley School District - August 2017 - May 2018

Internship

Following around different members of the department, learning about their jobs and helping them with any taks they had. I worked with computer repair technicians, server admins, Help Desk, warehouse workers, everyone that was needed to keep technology working for the school district.

YMCA of Boulder Valley - October 2017 - December 2018

Lifeguard

Maintain constant surveillance of patrons in the facility

Act immediately and appropriately to secure safety of patrons in the event of emergency

Provide emergency care and treatment as required until the arrival of emergency medical services

Monitor pool-related activities closely throughout shift and identify any safety issues

Discount Tire, Boulder, Colorado - December 2018 - August 2019

Tire Technician

Dismounting, mounting, balancing, rotating tires

Lifting or jacking the vehicle up properly and safely

Operating all related equipment and tools as trained

Operating independently and as a team member or leader

Selling and assisting customers in finding the best tires or wheels for their car

Handling scrap tires and organizing them into the bin for storage

Keeping the bays clean and orgaized

Apple Store Maine Mall October 2019 - Present

FWE Specialist

Uncovering customers needs

Provide solution to customers situation based on infornmation they provide or that is uncovered during probing

Advise, sell, and help setup a customers new device

Achievments

Top performer for Winter 2019 for Upper New England in Apple Care Sales

Skills

Teamwork, quick learner, strong spoken, verbal and written communication, leadership and managment, dependable, epathetic

Technologies

Ruby, Python, Linux, C++, HTML5, Git

Education

High School

Skyline High School

Gradutaion Year 2018 Graduated in the Spring of 2018 with a STEM diploma. Elective courses consisting of Computer Science and Application Development.

College

Front Range Community College

Currently taking classes related to chemistry, engineering, and mathematics.